Nikola Milinković

Full-Stack Engineer & Graduated Information Technology Engineer



11080 Zemun, Belgrade nikolamilinkovic221@gmail.com

+381 63 1202 585

PORTFOLIO WEBSITE

nikola-portfoliowebsite.vercel.app ☑

GITHUB

github.com/NikolaMilinkovic 🛮

EDUCATION

Information Technology School

2021 – 2024 | Belgrade, Serbia Graduated Engineer of Information Technologies

High School of Economic

2012 - 2016

Business Technician

COURSES

The Odin Project

Full-Stack Web Development Course

Front End Masters \square

Data Structures & Algorithms Course

LANGUAGES

Serbian - Native English - Fluent Japanese - Basic German - Basic

SUMMARY

Backed by a traditional programming-centric academic background, I made the decision to focus my efforts on becoming a full-stack developer. My self-taught journey has been difficult, but with strong determination, I've navigated complex problems and overcome significant challenges, ultimately becoming a better programmer in the process.

SKILLS

Languages — JavaScript | TypeScript

Front-end — HTML/CSS | React | React Native | SASS

Back-end — Express | Node.js

Database — SQL | MongoDB | Microsoft SQL Server

Other — Jest | Git | GitHub | Postman

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

February 2024 - present

Developed responsive web & mobile applications. using React & React Native. Collaborated with clients to gather requirements and deliver tailored solutions.

Game Design & World Builder, Game of Education

2021 - 2023

Contributed to the success of multiple top performing maps through planning | design | map testing, including "How to Live Inside an Axolotl", "TNT Tools" & "Summer Beach Bunker."

Frontend Web Developer, Golux Technologies doo ♂

January 2020 - November 2021 | Belgrade, Serbia

Implemented design solutions for multiple web apps. Ensured best user experience while keeping the high functionality of the design. Collaborated with design and backend teams to execute and implement the best solution.

PROJECTS

Infinity Boutique App

GitHub Front-end ☑ | GitHub Back-end ☑

Inventory management & order tracking application developed for prominent instagram boutique in Serbia.

- Technologies: TypeScript, ReactNative, NodeJs, Socket.io ☑, MongoDB, AWS S3, ChatGPT-4o-mini.
- Efficient inputs: ChatGPT used for parsing buyer data and inputing correct data into correct fields.
- Socket.io: Real time updates across all devices.
- AWS S3 for image storage & MongoDB for storing other data.

Portfolio Website

Live Demo 🖸 | GitHub repository 🖸

Personal portfolio website that showcases my skills, achievements, and projects.

- Interactive Chatbot: Custom ChatGPT 4o-mini API to answer questions about me based on pre-defined instructions.
- **Email Integration:** EmailJS library to handle form submissions, allowing users to send emails directly from the website.

Mc Schematic Manager

Live Demo ☑ | GitHub Front-end ☑ | GitHub Back-end ☑

Online tool for storing, managing, and retrieving .schematic files (type of file used to save and share structures in Minecraft).

- Efficient File Handling: Puppeteer script that optimizes the upload of .schematic files via third party service.
- **User Management Dashboard:** Dashboard for adding/removing users, managing permissions, and updating user information.

Battleship Game

<u>Live Demo</u> ☑ | <u>GitHub repository</u> ☑

Interactive web-based version of the classic Battleship game that features smart opponent.

• Computer Opponent: Algorithm that detects hits and continues targeting the same ship until it's sunk.